在这里，我们现在应该对我们非常熟悉。我们有一个坐标
Here we have something that should be quite familiar to us by now. We have a coordinate
框架表示A，我们有一个点。现在这一点正在发生变化。它有一个空间速度，
frame denoted A and we have a point. Now that point is moving. It’s got a spacial velocity,
nu，关于框架A和我用这种方式表示它。它具有平移速度
nu, with respect to frame A and I denote it this way. It’s got translational velocity
分量，X点和Y点以及旋转速度分量thetadot但是我代表
component, X dot and Y dot and a rotational velocity component theta dot but I represent
用一支箭头。
that by a single arrow.
现在我将介绍另一个坐标系，一个红色的协调框架，表示为B和
Now I am going to introduce another coordinate frame, a red coordinated frame denoted B and
我们有一个相对姿势来描述框架B相对于姿势的姿势
we have a relative pose that describes the pose of frame B with respect to the pose of
帧A.现在我还可以描述相对于坐标系的点的速度
frame A. Now I can also describe the velocity of the point with respect to coordinate frame
B和我通过使用领先的超级脚本B代替A来做到这一点。
B and I do that by using a leading super script B instead of A.
现在，点相对于帧B的速度与速度有关
Now, the velocity of the point with respect to frame B is related to the velocity with
相对于框架A，它与雅可比矩阵相关，雅可比矩阵映射速度
respect to frame A and it’s related by a Jacobian matrix, a Jacobian that maps velocity
从一帧到另一帧。
from one frame to another.
这种特殊的雅可比行列式是两帧之间相对姿态的函数。
This particular Jacobian is a function of the relative pose between the two frames.
它是一个三乘三的矩阵，包括相对姿势的旋转部分和
It’s a three by three matrix that comprises the rotational part of the relative pose and
一堆零和一个。实际上，它只是相对方向的函数
a bunch of zeros and ones. In fact, it is only a function of the relative orientation
帧之间。它完全不依赖于这两个帧的起源之间的距离。
between the frames. It doesn't depend at all on the distance between the origins of these two frames.